Hello everyone and welcome back. So um
we're going to open up I've closed the
folder because I assume at some point
you're going to close Visual Studio
Code. So I've closed a folder on our
website and I'm just going to reopen it
just so you have a reminder as how to do
that. So I'm going to come over here,
click the open folder button, and then I
have my folder on my desktop and then
here I've called it first website. So
highlight that and then click open. If
you're on a Windows, your Finder is
going to look a little different but the
steps are exactly the same. All right,
so we are back to where we were. This is
our HTML. Last time we talked about how
to use um the development tools to look
at our HTML and to look at our
JavaScript. So in this video we're going
to talk a little bit about comments. So
comments are pieces of code the computer
does not read. It completely ignores
those lines of code. It's very helpful
for a developer who's learning how to
document their code so that the next
developer who comes along knows what's
happening. Um, so if you want to put in
a comment for HTML, the way you put a
comment is you do the open carrot sign,
then an exclamation mark, and two
dashes. If you're in Visual Studio Code,
it will automatically fill in the
following part. But if you're ever not
in Visual Studio Code and your
environment doesn't fill it in, you'll
just close it with two dashes and then
the other carrot sign. Now, anything I
type here will not show up on the page.
So, I could say my first comment. Um,
but I'm going to use this comment for
what I would typically use this comment
for. So, this comment I usually put at
the top of every coding file so that
people know who changed the file last
and why they changed the file. So, I'm
going to say my name is Choa and I'm
going to give a description of what this
does. So I'm going to say this HTML file
is the hello world page. So now if
someone were to come along and try and
maintain this page later, they'll open
up my code and they'll see a description
and it says this page is for the hello
world page, which means if they're
having a error on the Hello World page,
they know this is the code they need to
look at. If they're having an error with
the welcome to the website page, then
they know it's not on this page. So, if
you give a description of what your
project does, it helps someone who comes
along later, and that someone could be
you. Um, sometimes you'll go back and
maintain your own code. You'll wonder
what you've done, and the comment helps
you know that. Um, so I'm going to add
another comment in the body.
Um, right here under Hello World, I'm
going to add another comment. The other
way you can put a comment is you can hit
command or if you're on Windows control
and then slash and it's the forward
slash that is right next to the right
shift key. So if I hit command slash, it
puts in the comment for me and I can
type this is my first comment and it
will not show up on the web page.
So if we save this as a reminder that's
command S or control S or you can come
up to the top and hit file and then save
and that'll save your file. If you have
your live server running from last time,
then you can just flip back over to the
browser and see what your web page looks
like. If you don't have it running, you
can come down here to the bottom right
hand corner and click this go live. As
soon as you click go live, it'll bring
you to your website where I still have
my developer tools open. And you can see
that it says hello world. You can also
see that it does not include our
comments on the page. If we want to see
those, we'll have to click over onto the
elements tab of the developer tool. And
then we can see our comment at the top
with our name and a description. And
then if we open up the body tag, we can
see our other comment as well as a
comment that was injected by our live
server. So these comments are all in
here and the developer can see them and
someone using the developer tools can
see them, but the average user will not
be able to see them. So that is how you
make an HTML comment. And I'm going to
stop the video there and in the next
video we'll talk about running your
first JavaScript and then JavaScript
comments.